Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1850-1859., 467 items. (Box 8-11)
    - Letters, 1853., 50 items. (Box-folder 9:1-50)
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to [Mildred W. Campbell], 25 July 1853., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:33)
        Expresses religious sentiments. She feels she is sinning by remaining at Shirley, but she cannot bring herself to leave her sinning husband. Family news. Rain is ruining wheat crop.
      - Geo[rge] Fred[erick] Holmes, Richmond to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 27 July 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:34)
        Inquires if he is writing an introductory Colonial History of Virginia for DeWitt's Lives of the Governors of Virginia. Such a sketch must be limited to 50 pages and submitted by 1 January 1854. Asks how much Campbell wishes to be paid for this effort.
      - Tho[mas] S. Gholson, Petersburg to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 1 August 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:35)
        Sends him lists of books to buy, but says they are incomplete.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], New York to Anna [Campbell],28 August 1853., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:36)
        Saw the burning of the Steamboat Cherokee; describes his day in New York City; will join her soon.
      - [Charles Campbell], New York to [?], 29 August 1853., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 9:37)
        Has visited some furniture stores looking for furniture for the Library. Two shipments of books will be sent tomorrow. Describes method of cataloguing and arranging the books. Describes the growth of New York City as "prodigious."
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Yonkers to Anna [Campbell],8 September 1853., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:38)
        Is glad to be out of "hot, dusty, crowded, odiferous, noisy, expensive" New York City; has traveled the Hudson by steamboat; plans to go back to Virginia.
      - A. D. Banks [?] to [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, 15 September 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:39)
        Directing Campbell to being writing short articles.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Shirley to Charles [Campbell], [c. October 1853]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:40)
        Hopes school is going well; baby is well; enjoying the country; thinks Quakers have a useful religion; cousin Mary not well.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 1 October 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:41)
        Asks them to make a bank draught on Peter Cogbill, treasurer of the Petersburg Library Association.
      - S. Hastings Grant, New York to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 12 October 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:42)
        Discusses various methods for cataloguing books and arranging them on the shelves.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to "cousin," 19 October 1853., 4 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 9:43)
        Enjoyed her visit; has been teaching; Charles Campbell is getting $50 per year from each student for classical instruction; Mary is walking and will be weaned soon.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Charles Folsom, [New York], 22 October 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:44)
        Says they are about to open a library and asks what best way to catalogue the books is.
      - Philip J. Forbes, New York to C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, 25 October 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:45)
        Suggests filing the books of the Petersburg Library under general subject headings rather than merely alphabetically by author. Suggests topical as well as alphabetical listing of books in the catalogue.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 14 November 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:46)
        Explains a confusion in buying books both from them and from Mr. Moffett for Petersburg Library. The Library is now all arranged and will open December 1.
      - William Maxwell, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 13 December 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:47)
        Mr. Grigsby has withdrawn his promise to speak at the next annual meeting. Requests Charles Campbell to come prepared to speak or read. Realizes is short notice, but knows Charles Campbell always has some article handy.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Editors of the Journal of Commerce,17 December 1853., 1 page. ADf. (Box-folder 9:48)
        Would like to contribute articles for compensation. Up to them to decide if content consistent with their interests.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 27 December 1853., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 9:49)
        Returns some books, most of which are duplicates sent to the Petersburg Library by mistake. Would prefer that a second edition of the History of Virginia be printed in the regular way rather than stereotyped.
      - [Anna Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to "cousin," 28 December 1853., 4 pages. Acy. (Box-folder 9:50)
        Is sewing and making a "slightly Quakerish" dress for herself; will get a new nurse for Mary; has weaned Mary; sister Mary's baby is not well.
    - Letters, 1854., 40 items. (Box-folder 9:51-90)
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Eliza, 11 January 1854., 3 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 9:51)
        Data on Edward Hill; list of portraits at Berkley.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Robert Paton, [New York], 30 January 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:52)
        Places order for desks and chairs to seat 30.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],1 February 1854., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:53)
        She returned to Shirley on 6 December 1853. Her husband continues to live in open sin, and tries to distract her from her own religious practices. Other family news. Frost has killed the wheat, and an attack of cholera is feared.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 10 February 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:54)
        Asks them to send a map with the next shipment of books. Asks them to get R. Paton to send the desks and chairs he ordered.
      - P[hilip] Slaughter, Fredericksburg to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 10 February 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:55)
        Inquires into a book sent to Campbell. He has been quite sick and so, for the foreseeable future, will be unable to deliver lectures. Sends congratulations on the opening of the Petersburg Library.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell to Charles [Campbell], 24 February 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:56)
        Molly's health "middling". She would like to move away from the country, and for Aleck to take up law again.
      - R. Baird, New York to [Charles] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 24 February 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:57)
        Would like to give a lecture series on Europe; asks Charles Campbell to publicize it.
      - Notice that Charles Campbell has been elected an Honorary Member of the State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 4 March 1854. (Box-folder 9:58)
        Signed by Lyman C. Draper.
      - Charles Campbell, [Petersburg] to Thomas S. Gholson, [Petersburg], 7 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:59)
        Encloses some statement on books in the Petersburg Library to be used in preparing the Annual Report.
      - Charles Campbell, Thomas Gholson, and A. B. Van Zandt, Petersburg to Matthew F. Maury, 7 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:60)
        Letter in Campbell's hand. Glad to hear he will deliver lecture; they will publicize the topic if he tells them what it is.
      - Thomas Balch, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 8 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:61)
        Wishes information, but prefers to ask if Charles Campbell is willing to help, before actually writing questions.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],11 March 1854., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:62)
        Has refrained from sending food promised for fear of it spoiling in unusually warm weather. Family, social news. Hopes to see her at Easter.
      - R. Baird, Norfolk, [Virginia] to [Charles] Campbell, [Petersburg, Virginia], 13 March 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:63)
        Will lecture before the Library Association.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 21 March 1854., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:64)
        Expresses surprise and regret that his work on the pioneers and George Rogers Clark has yet to be published. The Virginia Historical Society is gaining ground, but publication of the Historical Register has been suspended.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Rev. Dr. Baird, 28 March 1854., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 9:65)
        On Baird's lecture series.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to John Tyler, 31 March 1854., 1 page. ADf. (Box-folder 9:66)
        Thanks him for his letter accepting invitation to speak. Proposes John Tyler to speak on the 4th or 5th of May.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 31 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:67)
        Encloses bank draft in payment of his bill to Robert Paton.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 31 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:68)
        Encloses bank draft in payment of his bill to Robert Paton. Asks if catalogue of Petersburg Library could be printed by then.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to [Robert] Paton,[New York], 31 March 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:69)
        He paid D. Appleton and Co. the money necessary to cover his bill for school furniture.
      - M[ary] B. Carter to Mildred [W. Campbell],[April ? 1854]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:70)
        All are disappointed she has not come to see them. Encloses $10, asks her to buy some raisins and almonds.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to J. W. Randolph, 14 April 1854., 1 page. ADfS. (Box-folder 9:71)
        Discussion of Randolph's projected reprinting of old histories of Virginia (Smith's, Beverley's, Burks's).
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., 25 April 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:72)
        Encloses bank draft for payment of his outstanding bills to them.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to [Charles Campbell], [Petersburg], 5 May 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:73)
        Returns, with thanks, a scrapbook he had borrowed. Thanks him for report of Virginia Historical Society library, and praises the work done there.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg to G[eorge] W. Randolph, Petersburg, 13 May 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:74)
        Has received his bill; payment will be forwarded shortly. Has not seen his new edition of Jefferson's Notes on Virginia.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to J. W. Randolph, 28 May 1854., 3 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 9:75)
        Discussion of Campbell's opinions on how a reprint of Beverley's History of Virginia should be edited and/or modernized.
      - A. E. Peticolas to [?], 30 May 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:76)
        Sends a "most reliable and healthy virus."
      - Callaway Campbell, Spottswood Farm, Warrenton, Virginia to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,10 June 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:77)
        Has a cold; thought Montague would be sent to prison; helped Uncle Aleck build a hen house.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],26 June [1854]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:78)
        Inquires after health of Charles' wife, Anna. Family news; social news.
      - Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 29 July 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:79)
        Has been corresponding with Benson J. Loosing in an effort to join him in writing a book. A work on Daniel Boone is about 2/3 completed.
      - Anna Campbell, Shirley, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 26 September 1854., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:80)
        Mary is talking; Cally going to Petersburg; baby is well.
      - Anna C[ampbell], to "cousin," [October c. 1854]., 4 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 9:81)
        Has been home about a month; Miss E. Wilson is staying with her until after her "sickness."
      - Anna Campbell, Shirley to Charles [Campbell], 1 October 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:82)
        Misses him; children are well; Charles Campbell's school begins; Cally well.
      - Callaway [Campbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to Grandma [Mildred Walker Campbell], 17 October 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:83)
        Does not think it worth while to buy a membership certificate for the agricultural fair for Uncle Aleck; asks Mildred Walker Campbell to get fowls for him for the fair; Jimmy Parum, the carpenter, will make a coop; asks Mildred Walker Campbell to come for the fair.
      - Henry Kernot [?], New York to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 19 October 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:84)
        Has sent him [D. Appleton and Co.] a copy of their latest catalogue, and asks him to put a notice of it in a Petersburg paper.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Thomas H. Wynne, Richmond, 27 October 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:85)
        Acknowledges receipt of manuscripts he sent. They have engaged enough lecturers for the season, including William H. McGuffey. Talks of proper payment for articles published in the Messenger.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to Mildred [W. Campbell],8 November 1854., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:86)
        Just returned from trip to Petersburg. Heard three sermons while there. Social new from Shirley. She has been suffering from headaches. Encloses $20; asks her to buy some things.
      - Henry A. Wise, Ouancock, Virginia to A. B. Van Zandt, [Petersburg], 11 November 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:87)
        He will not be able to deliver a lecture on December 13. He will try to prepare a lecture for another time.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 22 November 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:88)
        On Campbell's suggestion, he will contact a Bishop Potter about giving a lecture to the Virginia Historical Society in January.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 3 December 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:89)
        Gives list of lecturers before Smithson[ian] Institution this winter; hopes to get one or two before Virginia Historical Society.
      - Tho[ma]s Gholson and A. B. Van Zandt, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 11 December 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:90)
        They ask him to deliver a lecture for the Petersburg Library Association.
    - Letters, 1855., 39 items. (Box 9-10)
      - Pasquale Vassetti, Portsmouth to [Charles Campbell], 31 January 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:91)
        Wants to sell his daguerreotype apparatus.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 31 January 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:92)
        Informs him that John M. Daniel's library is about to be sold at auction; suggests buying some for Petersburg City Library. Gives news of some up-coming lectures.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 28 February 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:93)
        Asks them to send and bill him for the listed items.
      - [Anna Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to "cousin," 5 March 1855., 4 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 9:94)
        Has new servants and pays $100 per year for 3 servants; Charles Campbell has 25 students.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to D. Appleton and Co., [New York], 6 March 1855., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 9:95)
        Requests they forward outstanding bills. Explains confusion over the non-payment of them.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to P[hilip] Slaughter,19 March 1855., 2 pages. ADf. (Box-folder 9:96)
        Pleased to hear he is going to edit [Hugh] Jones' "Present State".
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Thomas S. Gholson, [Petersburg], 22 March 1855., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 9:97)
        Acknowledges his re-election, but resigns his position on the Board of Managers of the Petersburg Library.
      - Callaway Campbell, New York to "Grandma" [Mildred Walker Campbell], 5 April 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:98)
        Has arrived safely in New York and is staying at the Astor House near Barnum's Museum; New York City is "hurry, bustle and confusion"; does not like having a room on an upper floor, visited Barnum's Museum; saw Campbell in Richmond.
      - J. Dudley Pendleton, Columbia, Fluvanna County, Virginia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 11 April 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:99)
        Asks questions about Robert Beverley.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to J. D. Pendleton, 21 April 1855., 1 page. ACy. (Box-folder 9:100)
        Is still seeking information on the Beverleys.
      - Callaway Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,23 April 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:101)
        Sorry that he would not see Campbell; garden is well; chicks have hatched.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley to [Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg], 23 April 1855., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:102)
        Her son Fitz and his wife are there, both ill. Family, domestic news. Asks her to buy some things for her and send them.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 27 April 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:103)
        Sends a copy of the Journal of Braddock's Ward, which he has not yet had the chance to read. Has also acquired a coy of The History of the Mason and Dixon Line, which he offers to lend Campbell at any time.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Thomas H. Wynne, [Richmond], 29 April 1855., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:104)
        Has read some of the material sent him, including an interesting article on the rise of the Know Nothing party. Is sorry to report to failing condition of the Virginia Historical Society.
      - Pasquale Vassetti, Portsmouth to [Charles] Campbell, 26 May 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:105)
        Thanks him for his help.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cleaveland to "Grandma" [Mildred Walker Campbell], 10 June 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:106)
        Is enjoying his stay at Cleaveland; Uncle Tom is awaiting the outcome of his lawsuit; Barkley McGhee has been drinking hard lately and his mind was affected by it.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cleveland, [Tennessee] to Mother [Anna Campbell], 13 June 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:107)
        Will visit the copper mines; visited Aunt Rebecca.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cleveland to Mildred W[alker] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 19 June 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:108)
        Uncle Tom won his law suit for $259,000 and is now suing a mining company; his pocket was picked; will go to Chota; Know Nothings and Democrats are contesting the Gubernatorial election; unusual locusts at Cleveland.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Trenton to Charles [Campbell], [c. July 1855]., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:109)
        Mary has been sick; Nanny learning to talk; normal school opened; needs money; rooms should be whitewashed; decided not to go to sister Mary's.
      - [Charles Campbell] has deposited $1500 in the bank, 14 July 1855., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 9:110)
      - C[allaway] Campbell, Comasanga, Georgia to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,[c. August 1855]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:1)
        Is no longer planning to visit Virginia; has visited Chota; Mary McPhee "is quite a business woman"; thinking about settling in Georgia; will send $76.
      - Cal[laway] Campbell, Cleveland, Tennessee to Grandma [Mildred Walker Campbell], 23 August [c. 1855]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:2)
        Has been visiting Uncle Tom's farm; will visit Chota; will visit Rhea County Springs.
      - Pasquale Vassetti, Portsmouth to [Charles] Campbell, 24 August 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:3)
        Disease in Norfolk.
      - Charles Campbell to Anna Campbell, Shirley, [c. September 1855]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:4)
        Charles Campbell's school starts the next day; social news.
      - B. T. Tinsley, Richmond, [Virginia] to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 10 September 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:5)
        Thanks him for his care of a sick man.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to "cousin," 16 September 1855., 4 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 10:6)
        Sympathy letter on Richard's death; helped a stranger with yellow fever.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to Anna [Campbell],25 September 1855., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:7)
        Family news; cargo of guano arrived in Petersburg; will pick her up next week.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to Callaway Campbell, [Chota, Tennessee], 27 September 1855., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:8)
        Yellow fever epidemic at Norfolk; school begins soon; teaching is a hard life; Mr. Maben in poor health.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cleveland to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,28 September 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:9)
        Does not expect John Maben to be well again; will visit Chota; does not want his fowls sold; asks for an Express, an Intelligencer, and a South Side.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, [Virginia] to Anna [Campbell],30 September 1855., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:10)
        Family news; is enjoying the peace and quiet; has 25 boys in his school.
      - Anna [Campbell], Shirley to Charles [Campbell], 3 October 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:11)
        Everyone well; house cleaning instructions.
      - G. F. H. Prockett [?], Chapel Hill, North Carolina to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 10 October 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:12)
        Offers to deliver a lecture to the Petersburg Library on "The Necessity of Revelation to the Knowledge of the Existence of God, Spirit, and Immortality."
      - Cal[laway] Campbell, Cleveland to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,13 October 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:13)
        Went to visit Uncle Tom's copper mines.
      - Callaway Campbell, Cleveland, Tennessee to M[ildred] W[alker] C[ampbell],26 [c. October 1855]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:14)
        Has visited Chota and the copper mines; two cousins are digging gold in California; family news.
      - Call[away] Campbell, Cleveland, Tennessee to M[ildred] W[alker] Campbell,4 November 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:15)
        Will start for Petersburg soon; she should keep his fowls and not give them away.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 9 November 1855., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:16)
        Is sorry not to have seen him recently. Has met with Dr. John McCabe, who is preparing a work on the churches of Virginia. Asks some historical questions. Asks him to send him a recent edition of the Southern Literary Messenger.
      - Anna [Campbell][?], Trenton to "cousin." William is leaving for the South; may be visiting, 12 November 1855., 4 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 10:17)
      - Pasquale Vassetti, Portsmouth to [Charles] Campbell, 13 November 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:18)
        Needs money.
      - Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut to [Charles Campbell], 5 December 1855., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:19)
        Will send him information on Ezekiel Cheever, foremost of early New England school-masters, and asks for information about a similar person in Virginia. Inquires in possibility of getting some Virginia subscribers to American Journal of Education.
    - Letters, 1856., 42 items. (Box-folder 10:20-61)
      - Callaway Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to "Grandma" [Mildred Walker Campbell], 3 February 1856., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:20)
        Joe, [a slave], has the chills.
      - Callaway Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to M[ildred] W[alker] C[ampbell],9 February 1856., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:21)